4kshooters.net 2019-06-16

# PRIVACY POLICY | 4K Shooters

For Press Enquiries, Press Releases and Review requests please use the following email: **4kshooters(at)gmail.com**

**Privacy Policy for 4KSHOOTERS.NET, owned by 4K MEDIA LTD**

As some of you may have already heard, the European Union has enacted a new major legislation called the EU General Data Protection Regulation or [GDPR](https://www.eugdpr.org/) for short, which takes effect at the end of May 2018 and relates to personal data and more importantly how companies hold your personal data and what they do with it.

Since we are EU based and we interact with many website readers from the EU, we’d like to make sure you know that we are fully compliant with the latest GDPR policy as well as fully transparent as to what we do with your data.

If you’d like to know more about the EU GDPR laws head over to this link, where you can learn more about it in greater detail: <https://www.eugdpr.org/>

In the interest of keeping it very simple and to the point – here is what you need to know.

· Protecting your private information is our absolute TOP priority.

**What Personal Info is Collected?**

The only personal information you provide to us is your email and name – which happens when you voluntarily opt-in to receive our weekly newsletter with industry updates and news, and/or to receive one of our FREE PDF Guides.

· We **DO NOT** sell or distribute your email and name to anyone or any organization period.

**How is my personal information used?**

From time to time, you may receive an email from us letting you know of a promotion, a new product, a tutorial or a new service that is offered by an advertiser, who have purchased an advertising service from us.

In this case, we **DO NOT** share your email with the advertiser, on the contrary, the information in such email marketing is sent to us by the advertiser and we use a third-party software to send this email to our email database, which includes your email and name – which are **NEVER** shared with the advertiser or any other third-party, other than the email marketing platform itself, which hosts the email database.

You can read Aweber Privacy Policy [here](https://www.aweber.com/privacy.htm).

**What about if I buy any of your products or click on any affiliate link from a blog post?**

For those of you who have purchased our [No Budget Filmmaking Guide](https://www.4kshooters.net/nobudgetfilmguide), we thank you very much, and we want to ensure you as well as those planning on purchasing the guide in the future, that the only information collected by GUMROAD (the third-party processing the payment and hosting of the guide and its data – more on their privacy policy and safe buying policy [here](http://help.gumroad.com/11167-Buyer-FAQ/safe-buying-on-gumroad)) are the payment information required.

You can pay with either Paypal or a Credit Card. We never see your payment details, and they are solely safeguarded by the respective third parties.

You may also purchase any of our affiliate products either from our Online Store or via any of the affiliate marketing links in any of our blog posts (to products sold on Amazon, B&H, Zacuto, and Adorama) and in such event, any personal data exchange is between you and the respective third party from which you are purchasing the product, as we are simply an affiliate partner, meaning that once you click on let’s say a B&H link – you will be automatically redirected to the B&H product page where you interact with the B&H website and our involvement ends.

We do get a small % commission should you chose to purchase the said product, at no extra cost to you of course. No personal details are exchanged between you or us (4KSHOOTERS.NET and 4K MEDIA LTD) at this point.

**What about Cookies?**

Our website uses cookies (both essential and non-essential), which means that some of them are necessary for the normal functionality of the website – i.e. they do not contain personal identifiers and cannot be declined as they are required to run the website. Other cookies may be used for internal analytics (see the next paragraphs below about Google Analytics) that contain top-level data – IP address and overall top-level location (for example – Denver, Colorado, USA – using Safari browser on a High Sierra macOS), as well as browser or OS, uses to access the site – and those are used in order to better your experience when browsing our website.

You have an option to decline such cookies via the opt-in plugin, which you have probably already seen when you load the website for the first time – you will get an automatic popup advising you that you can either accept or decline such cookies.

You can also disable cookies in your browser. We suggest consulting the Help section of your browser or taking a look at [the About Cookies website](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) which offers guidance for all modern browsers.

None of the information within such non-essential cookies is shared with third parties and is solely used for internal purposes in order for us to ensure the best possible experience for our visitors.

**Interest-based ads and Google Analytics**

We use popular and common analytics apps such as Google Analytics to track the performance of our website – [4kshooters.net](https://www.4kshooters.net/), which may include IP addresses and other top-level visitor data – such as which country you are visiting from and what browse you use. We cannot see (nor we want to or need to) your address, name, email and other personal identifiable data, which shows in the Google Analytics reports and other apps we use to track the performance of the website.

We use those reports to improve the website and see what content is read from where, so we can better serve the needs of our readership base.

This information gives us a general idea whether people use mobile devices or desktops to access our website and also which channels they come from – for example, some of you use Google to find us, others have clicked on a link to an article on a social media website such as Twitter or Facebook that we have shared.

We also may generate top-level reports of the general visitors for a specific time (for example – a report may show 350,000 visitors for April 2018 for example, and 42% of it from the US, but no personal identifiable data. We use this information for internal purposes such as making sure the site can load in a reasonable time without placing a strain on our servers or to give potential advertisers an idea of the numbers we get each moment.

However, and we’d like to stress here, we **HAVE NEVER** and **WILL NEVER** share with an advertiser your name or email address (which we only have access to from our email database – in the way that you have submitted to use voluntarily). Such information is not even available from the Google Analytics reports.

**How About Commenting on the Blog?**

Again, we **DO NOT** collect your personal data when leaving comments on the blog. All data, in this case, is gathered by Disqus. Disqus users can request access to all the information Disqus holds about them or request that the company completely deletes all of this information by emailing at [privacy@disqus.com](mailto:privacy@disqus.com).

**Opt-Out & Unsubscribe**

We respect your privacy, of course, you have the right to unsubscribe from our newsletter with a click of a button. All you have to do is click on the Unsubscribe button at the bottom of the newsletter email and you’re done. Alternatively, you could email us at 4kshooters(at)gmail.com with a request to do so, and we’ll remove you from our mailing list.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy or your personal data you can get in touch with 4K SHOOTERS and its respective owner 4K MEDIA LTD via email:

Email Address: 4kshooters(at)gmail.com
